<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="ext_idle_notify_v1">

  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2015 Martin Gräßlin
    Copyright © 2019-2025 Wayland contributors

    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
    copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
    to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
    the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
    and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
    Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including the next
    paragraph) shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the
    Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
    IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
    FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL
    THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
    LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
    FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER
    DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <description summary="idle notification protocol">
    This protocol allows clients to be notified when the user is idle for
    a given amount of time.

    A compositor may not support idle notifications at all, in which case
    the global will not be advertised.

    Warning! The protocol described in this file is currently in the
    staging phase. Backward compatible changes may be added together with
    the corresponding interface version bump. Backward incompatible changes
    can only be done by creating a new major version of the extension.
  </description>

  <interface name="ext_idle_notifier_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="idle notification manager">
      This interface allows a client to get notified when the user is idle.
    </description>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the idle notifier object" />
    </request>

    <request name="get_idle_notification">
      <description summary="create an idle notification object">
        This creates an idle notification with the given timeout. After
        the client has been idle for the specified amount of time, the
        compositor will send the idled event to the notification object.
        When the user becomes active again, the resumed event is sent.

        The notification object remains valid until the client destroys it,
        or the compositor cancels the notification (e.g., screen locks).
        The compositor may resume notifications after screen unlock.

        The timeout is given in milliseconds with a minimum of 100 ms.
      </description>
      <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="ext_idle_notification_v1" />
      <arg name="timeout" type="uint" summary="minimum idle time in ms" />
    </request>
  </interface>

  <interface name="ext_idle_notification_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="idle notification object">
      An idle notification object created by the idle notifier.
    </description>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the notification object" />
    </request>

    <event name="idled">
      <description summary="the user is now idle">
        This event is sent when the user has been idle for the time
        specified when creating the notification object.
      </description>
    </event>

    <event name="resumed">
      <description summary="the user is active again">
        This event is sent when the user is no longer idle.
      </description>
    </event>
  </interface>
</protocol>